{
    "1": {
        "question": "Who was the first Viceroy of India?\n(a)Lord Canning\n(b)Lord Curzon\n(c)Lord Mountbatten\n(d)Lord Wavell\n",
        "answer": "a",
        "more_info": "Lord Canning was the first Viceroy of India. The title of Viceroy was created in 1858 after the mutiny of 1857. Before 1858 East India Company was ruling large parts of India and the head of administration of the East India Company was called Governor General. This office was created in 1773. The title Governor General had administrative control over the British Provinces of India (Punjab Bengal Bombay Madras United Provinces etc.). After the mutiny of 1857 the British Government took control of the administration from East India Company. To reflect the Governor General's role as representative from the monarch the term Viceroy of India was applied to him. The title remained in existence from 1858 till 1947. Lord Caning was Governor General of India from 1856 to 1858 and Viceroy of India from 1858 to 1862.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "2": {
        "question": "Aurobindo Ghose Barindra Kumar Ghose B.P. Mitra Abinash Bhattacharya and Bhupendranath Dutta were associated with the revolutionary organization\n(a)Anushilan Samiti (in Bengal)\n(b)Satya Shodhak Samaj\n(c)Bengal Society\n(d)Lok Pal Party\n",
        "answer": "a",
        "more_info": "Aurobindo Ghose Barindra Kumar Ghose B.P. Mitra Abinash Bhattacharya and Bhupendranath Dutta were associated with the revolutionary organization Anushilan Samiti (in Bengal). The history of the Anushilan Samiti stretches from its beginning early in the first decade of 1900 to its gradual dissemination into the Congress-led Indian independence movement and into the Communist politics in India in the late 1930s. The Samiti began in the first decade of the 20th century in Calcutta as conglomeration of local youth groups and gyms.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "3": {
        "question": "When did the First World War begin?\n(a) 28th July 1914\n(b) 20th July 1913\n(c) 28th May 1900\n(d) 28th June 1914\n",
        "answer": "a",
        "more_info": "World War I also known as the First World War or the Great War and initially in North America as the European War was a global war originating in Europe that lasted from 28 July 1914 to 11 November 1918.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "4": {
        "question": "The Chinese traveller Hiuen Tsang called the prince of pilgrims visited India during the reign of?\n(a)Harsha\n(b)Chandragupta II\n(c)Dharampala\n(d)Devapala\n",
        "answer": "a",
        "more_info": "Hiuen Tsang was the Chinese traveler who visited India in Ancient Times between AD 627-643. He visited India during the reign of Harshavardhana (Harsha) who came to admire him for his deep devotion towards Buddhism.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "5": {
        "question": "Which one of the following scripts of ancient India was written from right to left?\n(a)Brahmi\n(b)Kharoshti\n(c)Nandnagari\n(d)Sharada\n",
        "answer": "b",
        "more_info": "The Kharoshi script is an ancient script used by the ancient Gandhara culture of South Asia primarily in modern-day Afghanistan and Pakistan to write the Gandhari language (a dialect of Prakrit) and the Sanskrit language.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "6": {
        "question": "The First Round Table was held on?\n(a)November 12 1930\n(b)December 12 1930\n(c)November 12 1937\n(d) October 12 1930\n",
        "answer": "a",
        "more_info": "First Round Table Conference was held between November 1930 and January 1931. It was officially inaugurated on November 12 1930 at House of Lords at London by the British King (George V) and was chaired by then British Prime Minister Ramsay MacDonald.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "7": {
        "question": "Who is known as Man of Blood and Iron?\n(a)Napoleon\n(b)Bismarck\n(c)Ho Chi Minh\n(d)Sir Walter Scott\n",
        "answer": "b",
        "more_info": "'Napoleon' is also known as Man of Destiny\n'Ho Chi Minh' is also known as Uncle Ho\n'Sir Walter Scott' is also known as Wizard of the North.\nOtto von Bismarck (Prince Bismarck) called \u201cman of blood\u201d from his great war policy and \u201ciron\u201d from his indomitable will. Many years Chancellor of Prussia and Germany. (Born September 1st 1815)",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "8": {
        "question": "In which year Hitler became the Chancellor of Germany?\n(a)1932\n(b)1933\n(c)1944\n(d)1945\n",
        "answer": "b",
        "more_info": "On January 30 1933 President Paul von Hindenburg names Adolf Hitler leader or f\u00fchrer of the National Socialist German Workers Party (or Nazi Party) as chancellor of Germany.Hitler\u2019s emergence as chancellor on January 30 1933 marked a crucial turning point for Germany and ultimately for the world. His plan embraced by much of the German population was to do away with politics and make Germany a powerful unified one-party state. He began immediately ordering a rapid expansion of the state police the Gestapo and putting Hermann Goering in charge of a new security force composed entirely of Nazis and dedicated to stamping out whatever opposition to his party might arise.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "9": {
        "question": "The term \u201cCold War\u201d was coined by?\n(a)Palmer Perkins\n(b)Prof. Lippmann\n(c)Bernard Baruch\n(d)Roosevelt\n",
        "answer": "c",
        "more_info": "Bernard Baruch the multimillionaire financier and adviser to presidents from Woodrow Wilson to Harry S. Truman coined the term \u201cCold War\u201d to describe the increasingly chilly relations between two World War II Allies the United States and the Soviet Union.",
        "user_response": "None"
    },
    "10": {
        "question": "The Indian National Congress was founded by?\n(a) A.O.Hume\n(b) Bal Gangadhar Tilak\n(c) Motilal Nehru\n(d) Surendranath Banerjee\n",
        "answer": "a",
        "more_info": "On 28 December 1885 the Indian National Congress was founded at Gokuldas Tejpal Sanskrit College in Bombay with 72 delegates in attendance. Hume assumed office as the General Secretary and Womesh Chunder Bonnerjee of Calcutta was elected President.",
        "user_response": "None"
    }
}